<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>retrospectives on VIE</title>
    <link>https://jamvie.net/categories/retrospectives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in retrospectives on VIE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamvie.net/categories/retrospectives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DEFCON 31: Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2023/08/defcon-31-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2023/08/defcon-31-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Beginning Back in October of 2019, I was attending my 3rd/4th? year at UBC, where I tried to play in a beginner-friendly CTF known as &amp;ldquo;CSAW 2019&amp;rdquo; with UBC&amp;rsquo;s team: Maple Bacon. Particularly, I tried out a challenge called Unagi, which, having spent an eternity on, I managed to solve after hours of wrangling with the problem.
To be completely frank, I solved the challenge after googling &amp;ldquo;XML vulnerability&amp;rdquo; and trying out payloads - really, just, throwing payloads and modifying them to tailor the challenge - until one stuck and I got the flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEFCON 30: Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/08/defcon-30-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 13:37:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/08/defcon-30-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Man.
My team, Maple Bacon, collaborated with CMU&amp;rsquo;s CTF team PPP and Theori.io&amp;rsquo;s CTF team The Duck, forming Maple Mallard Magistrates as a merger to participate in DEF CON finals.
The Beginning Discussions about the merge had occurred earlier in the year - I triangulate it to a month or so before I found myself in Athens, Greece attending ICC. This is important to mention as I heard many people speculate about the existence of MMM and whether or not it was formed as a response to something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MapleCTF UBC ver. Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/01/maplectf-ubc-ver.-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 22:00:18 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/01/maplectf-ubc-ver.-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Jan 21-28 marked the inaugural MapleCTF: UBC version, Maple Bacon&amp;rsquo;s first CTF to hit the scene.
For our very first, we wanted to keep it local. This made it very different from most other CTFs that one would be used to. We treated this as a beginner event - hoping to introduce the UBC community to the concept, well aware that we would have to cater to varying skill levels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
