<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>misc on Jam Polintan</title>
    <link>https://jamvie.net/tags/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in misc on Jam Polintan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 20:57:15 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamvie.net/tags/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VolgaCTF Finals 2020</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2020/09/volgactf-finals-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 20:57:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2020/09/volgactf-finals-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A reflection on VolgaCTF Finals, which I participated in with my team. We were the only North American team participating in the event, and for a good portion of the CTF, we held 1st place! Unfortunately, that didn&amp;rsquo;t last for the end of the competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography and P vs. NP: A Basic Outline</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2020/07/cryptography-and-p-vs.-np-a-basic-outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:22:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2020/07/cryptography-and-p-vs.-np-a-basic-outline/</guid>
      <description>Comic from XKCD.
I am not an expert in either cryptography nor algorithm analysis. However, ever since a very rewarding advanced algorithm analysis class, one question has always dwelled in my mind: what would &amp;ldquo;P=NP&amp;rdquo; mean for cryptography? I had heard that such a statement, &amp;ldquo;P=NP&amp;rdquo; is controversial in the world of security. Learning about algorithm complexity has certainly shed quite a bit of light on the topic. As a cybersecurity researcher, I was compelled to satisfy my curiosity and answer that question for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commonly Used Software</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2020/04/commonly-used-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 01:30:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2020/04/commonly-used-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really like web-based exploits, so I focus primarily on the web challenges when my team and I participate in CTFs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamvie&#39;s first post</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2020/04/jamvies-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 21:27:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2020/04/jamvies-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hi, and welcome to my CTF blog. I&amp;rsquo;m just a software dev with a hobby for CTFs, and I thought a blog would be a good way to stash all my long-archived writeups for CTF challenges I participated in. I&amp;rsquo;m by no means an expert on the topic, but if someone stumbles upon here and gains a newfound interest in cybersecurity, that would be pretty cool.
Over the next few weeks I will upload my old writeups for some CTFs that occurred this year and last, so stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>