<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VIE</title>
    <link>https://jamvie.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on VIE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:30:33 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jamvie.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DEFCON 33: Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2025/08/defcon-33-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 16:30:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2025/08/defcon-33-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>1 CTF. 2 full days of hacking. 3 teams. 4 victories.&#xA;When we won last year, our hat-trick, we were the first in DEF CON&amp;rsquo;S history to do it. 3 consecutive victories, 8x3 (24) black badges awarded in 3 total years. I think it was safe to say that a reputation formed around us and naturally, speculation. PPP and The Duck already had their own reputations so it&amp;rsquo;s not like the secrets and rumors and awe towards MMM came out of nowhere.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DEF CON 32 Retrospective, end of the year recap</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2024/12/def-con-32-retrospective-end-of-the-year-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 10:29:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2024/12/def-con-32-retrospective-end-of-the-year-recap/</guid>
      <description>In 2009, a group students at the Carnegie Mellon University formed a computer security club known as the Plaid Parliament of Pwning, abbreviated to PPP, to participate in Capture the Flag contests. The team saw numerous successes throughout their tenure, and many of the CMU folks with their roots in PPP went on to succeed professionally in cybersecurity-related careers.&#xA;2 such members went on to co-create Theori.io, a leading platform of security solutions covering everything from security education to audits and consulting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DUCTF 2024: Prisoner Processor</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2024/07/ductf-2024-prisoner-processor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 10:29:46 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2024/07/ductf-2024-prisoner-processor/</guid>
      <description>DUCTF 2024 has concluded this summer, and I decided to take a look at it with Maple Bacon and solve a few challenges. This is specifically a writeup for &amp;ldquo;Prisoner-Processor&amp;rdquo;, the hardest web challenge available. My teammate Angus and I solved this together. It was a great challenge and ventured into alot of interesting things about Bun and TypeScript, so kudos to the authors for making such an interesting challenge!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A case for documentation</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2024/01/a-case-for-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 22:23:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2024/01/a-case-for-documentation/</guid>
      <description>I am aware that the main target audience of my tiny blog are CTF players looking for my writeups and other like-minded security researchers exploring topics I like. But my 2024 resolution was to relive and unite my artistic persona that I spent most of my teen years curating, and marrying that to the security career life I live now. Part of my fine arts training involved a good deal of literature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAPLECTF 2023: JUJUTSU KAISEN</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2023/10/maplectf-2023-jujutsu-kaisen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 19:53:16 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2023/10/maplectf-2023-jujutsu-kaisen/</guid>
      <description>MapleCTF&amp;rsquo;s 2nd annual CTF was held at the same time as Hackceler8 preparation week, so for a brief couple of days in Japan I was busy helping organize 2 ctfs at once, which I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend.&#xA;This year, I decided to spice things up with my chals, my vie chals, by incorporating a fun prize for whichever team manages to solve all of my challenges.I had 3 challenges: JaVieScript, Blade Runner, and Jujutsu Kaisen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DEFCON 31: Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2023/08/defcon-31-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2023/08/defcon-31-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Beginning Back in October of 2019, I was attending my 3rd/4th? year at UBC, where I tried to play in a beginner-friendly CTF known as &amp;ldquo;CSAW 2019&amp;rdquo; with UBC&amp;rsquo;s team: Maple Bacon. Particularly, I tried out a challenge called Unagi, which, having spent an eternity on, I managed to solve after hours of wrangling with the problem.&#xA;To be completely frank, I solved the challenge after googling &amp;ldquo;XML vulnerability&amp;rdquo; and trying out payloads - really, just, throwing payloads and modifying them to tailor the challenge - until one stuck and I got the flag.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PBCTF 2023 : JAZZY x VIE CHALS</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2023/02/pbctf-2023-jazzy-x-vie-chals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 15:25:54 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2023/02/pbctf-2023-jazzy-x-vie-chals/</guid>
      <description>I was a guest challenge writer for perfect blue&amp;rsquo;s CTF held mid February. We play-tested each others chals :P&#xA;MAKIMA Challenge Description Makima simps check in here&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m actually a Power stan. I just needed an excuse for people to look at my Makima drawing.&#xA;TL;DR Hide php in image, making a PHP/image polyglot X-Accel-Header redirection through CDN to reach internal .php files and access /uploads/your_img.png/lol.php to execute PHP The important parts The default.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MapleCTF 2022    : Vie&#39;s challenges</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/09/maplectf-2022-vies-challenges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 14:50:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/09/maplectf-2022-vies-challenges/</guid>
      <description>MapleCTF 2022 ran this year to great success, which is fantastic given the tight timeframe we were operating on shortly after coming back from DEFCON 30. We held a beginner-friendly, UBC-local version back in January, so our endgame for this version was to make more creative and harder challenges that people hopefully enjoyed. I wrote 3 web challenges for this CTF: honksay, Viene Library and Art Gallery, the latter 2 I will detail here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DEFCON 30: Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/08/defcon-30-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 13:37:54 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/08/defcon-30-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Man.&#xA;My team, Maple Bacon, collaborated with CMU&amp;rsquo;s CTF team PPP and Theori.io&amp;rsquo;s CTF team The Duck, forming Maple Mallard Magistrates as a merger to participate in DEF CON finals.&#xA;The Beginning Discussions about the merge had occurred earlier in the year - I triangulate it to a month or so before I found myself in Athens, Greece attending ICC. This is important to mention as I heard many people speculate about the existence of MMM and whether or not it was formed as a response to something.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NahamCon CTF 2022</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/05/nahamcon-ctf-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 12:40:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/posts/2022/05/nahamcon-ctf-2022/</guid>
      <description>Just in Time Maple Bacon played in NahamCon CTF 2022 this past weekend, which came as a surprise - we were fully planning on focusing our efforts onto AngstromCTF which overlapped, however, NahamCon CTF proved to be interesting and good-quality so a last-minute decision was made to participate in both. AngstromCTF is still underway, but in the awkward passage of time between my last week and weekend, I played in NahamCon CTF for a little bit of practice.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
