<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jamvie: CTF writeups and more</title>
    <link>https://jamvie.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jamvie: CTF writeups and more</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 15:20:38 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamvie.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>De1ctf 2020: Hard_Pentest_1 and Animal Crossing, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/05de1ctf2020_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 15:20:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/05de1ctf2020_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The intersection of web-based challenges and other challenges should be expected to be seen in CTFs, but yet still I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised when I see it in action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plaidctf 2020: Contrived Web Problem</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/04plaidctf2020_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:48:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/04plaidctf2020_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a CTF I unfortunately didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time for, as I was busy doing finals in April :(. My team let me know about this cool and unique problem, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad they did!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commonly Used Software</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/03toolsofthetrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 01:30:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/03toolsofthetrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really like web-based exploits, so I focus primarily on the web challenges when my team and I participate in CTFs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CONfidence 2020: CatWeb</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/02confidence2020_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:46:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/02confidence2020_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I participated in CONfidence CTF 2020 teasers in March of this year. I was focusing mainly on this problem, and it really helped me broaden my skills in JSON-related attacks! I have never seen many JSON injections before this, so this was welcome practise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>utctf 2020: Epic Admin Pwn</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/01utctf01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:46:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/01utctf01/</guid>
      <description>I particpated in UTCTF with my team in March 2020, held and operated by the University of Texas ISSS. My team and I solved a very fun SQLi-based attack! This challenge helped me to refine my python skills cause the lord knows I needed it, as well as reinforced my knowledge about SQL-based attacks. This is the first web challenge I solved in the CTF, and admittedly the one that I enjoyed the most to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jamvie&#39;s first post</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/00initialpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 21:27:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/00initialpost/</guid>
      <description>Hi, and welcome to my CTF blog. I&amp;rsquo;m just a software dev with a hobby for CTFs, and I thought a blog would be a good way to stash all my long-archived writeups for CTF challenges I participated in. I&amp;rsquo;m by no means an expert on the topic, but if someone stumbles upon here and gains a newfound interest in cybersecurity, that would be pretty cool.
Over the next few weeks I will upload my old writeups for some CTFs that occurred this year and last, so stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>