<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>writeups on Jam Polintan</title>
    <link>https://jamvie.net/tags/writeups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in writeups on Jam Polintan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>CC Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 21:47:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamvie.net/tags/writeups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 HackASat Quals</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/07hackasat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 21:47:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/07hackasat/</guid>
      <description>I participated in HackASat Quals with my team earlier in May. This was a unique CTF, as it had a category of astrodynamic mathematical problems that pertained to the geometry of earth-orbiting objects. I love math, so I actually quite enjoyed this category! 2 teammates and I collaborated together to solve a specific problem known as &amp;ldquo;I Like to Watch.&amp;rdquo; I also went through it myself and am going to discuss my solution to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSAW 2019: Unagi</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/06csaw2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 01:22:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/06csaw2019/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2019 I really got into CTFs as a matter of honing my security skills. They were fun to do and enriched my knowledge of cybersecurity - so I got into it pretty quickly.
This was among the first of the challenges I did while under my team, Maple Bacon. At the time, I had plenty experience with SQL injections and XSS attacks, but not nearly enough experience with another common vulnerability: XXE attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DE1ctf 2020: Hard_Pentest_1 and Animal Crossing</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/05de1ctf2020_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 15:20:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/05de1ctf2020_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The intersection of web-based challenges and other challenges should be expected to be seen in CTFs, but yet still I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised when I see it in action.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plaidctf 2020: Contrived Web Problem</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/04plaidctf2020_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:48:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/04plaidctf2020_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a CTF I unfortunately didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time for, as I was busy doing finals in April :(. My team let me know about this cool and unique problem, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad they did!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CONfidence 2020: CatWeb</title>
      <link>https://jamvie.net/post/02confidence2020_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:46:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamvie.net/post/02confidence2020_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I participated in CONfidence CTF 2020 teasers in March of this year. I was focusing mainly on this problem, and it really helped me broaden my skills in JSON-related attacks! I have never seen many JSON injections before this, so this was welcome practise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>